<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Connor Yager</title>
    <description>My personal website, where I keep updates on projects that I'm working on,  notable events in my life, and other such information.  
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 09:52:28 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 09:52:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>GreekRho Beta Launch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is on Github!  Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/csyager/greeklink-core&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left; margin-right: 20px; width: 25%; min-width: 250px&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/greekrho_launch/logo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/greekrho_launch/logo.png&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail figure-img img-fluid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to announce that GreekLink has been officially rebranded as GreekRho, and that we’ve begun our beta testing phase with organizations on grounds at UVA!  We’re starting small, using my fraternity Delta Sigma Phi and another member of the team’s fraternity Alpha Sigma Phi as beta testers, but we’re really excited to be working with clients and shaping the direction of the site’s development alongside them.  While this semester certainly won’t look how we had planned, with social and recruiting events effectively on standby until the end of the semester, it’s our hope that we can get enough hands on the site that we can figure out what needs to be changed and what features need to be added or expanded, so that the application is best ready to help organizations hit the ground running once things get back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that our application has the potential to seriously disrupt the existing standard for student organizations.  From experience in my own fraternity, we pay hand over foot for subscriptions to segmented services that only solve one or two of our problems at a time.  For example, we pay hefty subscription fees for a financial application that tracks dues payments and provides an online location for submitting payments each semester.  We rely on UVA’s infrastructure for communicating among our members, with little to no privacy of that communication.  We have historically not paid for a rush service, because it’s too expensive and doesn’t offer services that are shaped by our rush practices.  GreekRho hopes to solve many of these problems by offering a central location for all of these services, offering it at a competitive price that beats out what any one of those services would demand, and shaping the service alongside the organizations that use it to ensure that the organization gets everything it needs and nothing it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of that initiative is that our project is &lt;b&gt;open source&lt;/b&gt;!  If you’re technically motivated, please feel free to make contributions to our project on Github!  We value feedback from users so highly that we welcome contributions to our source code, and believe that this collaborative approach will make us more able to interface with our clients.  For those users who are less technically inclined, we’ve put a huge emphasis on our support feature, which allows users to submit feature requests, bug reports, and any general feedback so we know what they want and what they don’t.  Additionally, our service is built on Amazon Web Services, and while so far we’ve been able to build within the free tier, passing no cost on to our users or ourselves, we want to accurately gauge the usage of the site, so we can better plan for the costs to operate the site.  This means that once we inevitably need to start charging for the usage, we can determine a fair price to pass to the users without ripping them off on exorbitant subscription fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve said, I really couldn’t be more excited to be bringing this site to a user base.  Creating applications that serve a purpose is my passion, and seeing a project get use and grow is the most fulfilling thing I do.  If you would like more information regarding the beta, or are interested in what GreekRho could do for you and your organization, shoot us an email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@greek-rho.com&quot;&gt;support@greek-rho.com&lt;/a&gt;.  There’s a lot more work to be done on the site, and a lot more growth to come!  Keep an eye out for our next release and our next great feature!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/19/greek-rho-launch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/19/greek-rho-launch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Server Maintenance Taught Me a Lesson About Cybersecurity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a little project about a year and a half ago, I decided to learn a little about networking and turn an old laptop into a server I could run from home.  As I’ve stated in other posts, that used to be where I hosted an older version of this site, as well as servers for games I could play with my friends and other fun stuff like that.  When I decided to build a web app for my fraternity to use during rush, I wanted to use that server to host that site.  Of course this wasn’t really the optimal solution, and eventually connections to the server mysteriously started to be rejected.  On a time crunch for the fraternity site, I decided to abandon it for the time being and look for alternative hosting options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend I decided to reopen the case and get to the bottom of why it stopped working.  It turned out to be a pretty silly oversight on my part.  Since the router that was forwarding requests to my server was the same Verizon router that my family uses in the house, it isn’t configured with a static IP address, and Verizon changed the address on me, hence why none of my requests were going through.  Pretty dumb mistake that wasted several hours of my time, but while investigating the issue I stumbled upon something that made me a little more concerned.  While taking a look at my ssh logs to figure out why my connections weren’t going through, I noticed that about every 10 seconds some new username was getting rejected.  The usernames were common, like “sysadmin,” or “john,” or “root,” and all would of course be rejected because I don’t have any user accounts using those names.  Even if they did get through the first username check, they would have to know my password to get in.  Regardless, this got me thinking though about the consequences of someone getting access to my computer.  In all honesty there’s not a lot that could be taken from me personally, but it could be used to monitor our internet access, run programs that I don’t want using my computer, or worse, spread malware to other computers.  All not great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last summer while working as a cybersecurity intern, I was pretty bored one day and wanted to check out just how important some of the priciples I was learning were.  So I downloaded a popular open source password cracker called John the Ripper.  The premise behind the program was pretty simple, you supply it with a long word list of common passwords and phrases, and it tries to programmatically crack the password.  Pretty simple, and in my eyes benign.  My password was not listed among the common phrases, so I thought I would be pretty safe.  Just as an experiment, I ran it against my root password.  Between probably 30 seconds and a minute later, the program read my password back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away.  My password certainly wasn’t as great as it should be, but its not terrible.  Still, this was a free program I downloaded and ran on my lunch break.  Anybody could have done this.  Honestly, it scared me pretty straight.  The good news is the botnets that are trying to get into my server at home aren’t doing anything this complicated, because it honestly isn’t worth the computing power.  It makes more sense to cast a wide net and find the one person using root/password as their login credentials than it does to focus on any one target.  But the lesson is the same, hiding access to my computer behind a flimsy username and password combination isn’t going to cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this problem, I took a couple of steps that I should have done from the get go.  First, in my ssh configuration, I turned off password access and required an RSA key instead.  Then I used ssh keygen to set myself up with a private key to ensure that even if someone got the username/password combo right, they still wouldn’t get anywhere without a verified private key.  Still though, this did nothing to take care of the enormous amounts of login attempts the server was seeing every day.  To combat this issue, I installed Fail2ban, a popular blacklisting tool that catches IP addresses trying too many times to get in.  Within about 10 minutes of starting the Fail2ban program I’ve caught 45 IP addresses, from locations including South Korea, China, and even within the US.  While these places likely don’t reflect the origin of the attackers, there is a clear diversity in the attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story, you can’t be too careful.  Even if you’ve never had problems before or feel confident in your password, a simple username/password check probably isn’t going to cut it for anything open to the internet.  And check your access logs every once in a while!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 19:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/12/server-maintanance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/12/server-maintanance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Developer Associate Course</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/course/aws-certified-developer-associate-dva-c01/&quot;&gt;Link to the Udemy Course I’m using to prepare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I have this big chunk of time between the end of school and when I’m hoping to be starting my job, I decided that I should spend some of that time preparing for future work and making myself a better developer.  Through my internships I’ve noticed a growing trend:  the cloud is everything.  In fact, through my personal work I’ve come face to face with that trend too.  Take the website I was running for my fraternity.  It became pretty clear after a few outages that running the site from a webserver on an old laptop in my house wasn’t a very good idea.  I just wasn’t able to develop, deploy new features, and worry about the server at the same time. (not to mention the server was at my parent’s house, so unless I could fix problems by ssh’ing into it from school I was basically relaying instructions to my mom.  Not great.)  At the time I took a lot of pride in being able to run the project at such a low cost, so it was a big hit to my ego to cough up $7 a month for a Heroku subscription.  In hindsight, not a big price to pay for the ease of deployment and guarantee of availability that heroku provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m looking to scale that project out to offer the same services to many more organizations.  It was clear to me when I started this that I would need to be able to leverage the cloud to support my project, and that the more control I had over how that was done, the better our service would be and the more affordable we could make it.  Having worked around AWS before, I decided that that was the technology we were going to use, and began learning the basics of their elastic beanstalk offering.  It didn’t take long before I was thoroughly overwhelmed by the number of services AWS provides, as well as the depth and complexity of each.  Between past experiences of the viability and future of the cloud, as well as my present needs, I realized that the cloud was something that I would need to be familiar with, and would benefit greatly from knowing as much as possible about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what inspired me to start the Udemy course linked above.  I try to knock out one section a day, and hopefully by the time I’m done with it I’ll have enough knowledge to pass the AWS Developer Associciate exam and earn my certification.  I believe that this will help to make me a more well-rounded developer, as well as make me a more attractive candidate for positions that require the use or understanding of the cloud.  Thus far, I’m surprised at how much I’ve learned, and how much more familiar the AWS console is feeling.  I’m looking forward to being a certified cloud expert, and am really enjoying this path of growth that I’ve started on!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 18:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/26/aws-cert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/26/aws-cert.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shifting Boundary Between Open-Source and Proprietary Software and its Role in the Future of AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.18130/v3-fabt-as11&quot;&gt;Click here to view my thesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The genesis of the open-source software development methodology in the 1990s effectively divided the professional software development world into two distinct groups: those individuals and corporations who support free and open-source software and those who support the traditional proprietary model. Today, these lines have become blurred, as proprietary corporations pledge support for the open-source community while open-source developers demand the acceptance of stricter licensing options. With the advent of human-level artificial intelligence on the horizon, this shifting spectrum of code ownership and profitability has great ethical implications, as the most equitable ownership of a technology primed to change the lives of all people comes into question. In the development of human-level artificial intelligence, the most destructive potential bug in its design is bias. In the same way that human bias is largely dependent on background, AI bias is based on faulty data. This data is the result of human-created algorithms that fail to accurately account for perspectives outside of those of its creator. The open-source vs. proprietary debate extends into this field, with the open-source community championing collective code-ownership, while proprietary supporters promise more rigorous safety testing and quality assurance. While it is difficult to make predictions about future technologies, evaluating the evolving relationship between open-source and proprietary technologies with respect to bias is an essential step in safety-engineering artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the capstone project, fourth year engineers at UVA are required to complete a senior thesis through the Science, Technology and Society department.  This project is also a year-long endeavor, and requires the student to research a technology or system and analyze the interaction between its technicalogical aspects and the social forces that shaped it.  My thesis was titled “The Shifting Boundary Between Open-Source and Proprietary Software and its Role in the Future of AI,” and analyzed the social forces shaping AI today, and how that might shape the development of human-level artificial intelligence in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is meant to relate to the technical capstone project.  The Power of Difference Assessment, which I talk about in another post, is an implicit bias assessment.  The angle of future AI research that I wanted to focus on was bias in artificial intelligence, and how that might affect systems of human-level intelligence.  While much of the paper is focused on the social evolutions that shape open-source and proprietary development methods, I use this analysis to discuss the pros and cons of the two methods and the way they have intersected when it comes to developing human-level artificial intelligence in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that human-level artificial intelligence is a technology that is evolving at a pace that will make it a reality in the near-future, and will have far-reaching applications for all humans.  However, existing versions of AI have proven in many arenas to be poorly thought-out, leading to misrepresentation of people that weren’t considered by the creators or injustice perpetuate by faulty data.  In the essay, I use the example of predictive policing, which is the practice of using AI to analyze crime data to better inform police officers about where and when they should patrol.  In theory, this should prevent crimes.  However, the data used to train these decision making algorithms was based on past arrests, which have historically been heavily biased towards minority neighborhoods.  This is a human bias that became machine bias because of the way that the software was designed.  Human-level AI will in all likelihood make decisions much more far-reaching and impactful, and it is my belief that progressing at the rate that we are today without stopping to make absolutely sure we have considered all people and the implications against them, we may accidentally create something that will devastate humanity rather than assist it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/21/ststhesis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/21/ststhesis.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Power of Difference Assessment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is on Github!  Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uva-cp-1920/The_Sum&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-bottom: 2%; width: 50%; margin-right: 2%; border-style: solid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/powerofdifference/landing.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/powerofdifference/landing.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Sum is a Charlottesville-based non-profit, with the stated goal of helping people learn about their implicit biases and understand how to better communicate with people of other backgrounds. Their Power of Difference Assessment, or PDA, is a tool used to identify these implicit biases and collect data that professionals at The Sum can use to consult the assessment taker. Under the initial PDA system, a lack of automation prevented scaling to a larger user base, restricting the growth of the organization and its ability to collect data. Our team was tasked with enhancing the system with features that would allow it to serve as a tool in institutional studies, with the ability to support thousands of assessment-takers and collect meaningful data for use in research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the UVA engineering curriculum, all fourth year students are required to complete a capstone project, meant to be the culmination of what they have learned over their four years.  For computer science students, this meant that we would be creating a project based on the requirements and specifications of a client, who was not necessarily of a technical background.  At the beginning of the year several clients came to our classroom to pitch their projects to us, and we ranked our favorite choices to find a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My project was with a nonprofit in the Charlottesville area called The Sum.  The Sum’s stated goal is to stand in solidarity with all people, and to take strides towards a more just and equitable world for people of all backgrounds.  One of their offerings towards this end is the Power of Difference Assessment, which is an online assessment that helps identify implicit biases.  By first answering 19 demographics questions and then rating their agreement or disagreement to 70 statements, consultants at The Sum can collect enough data to have a meaningful conversation with the assessment taker about their implicit biases and how they can combat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our job was to take the existing system, which was thrown together somewhat haphazardly using some Javascript and HTML, and create a new system that could scale to thousands of users so the assessment could be used for institutional studies.  In its original form, the assessment could only handle one test taker at a time, and relied heavily on the consultants at The Sum to collect the data manually when they were done before they could compile a report on the results.  This obviously wouldn’t work if thousands of people were taking the assessment, so we had to automate everything from starting the test and collecting basic contact information from the user to scheduling consultations when the assessment was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project resonated with me in a lot of ways.  First, being interested in consulting it was fun to be working with a client.  I find that the most enjoyable parts of engineering are not when I have to sit by myself and grind on work quietly, but when I can interact with others and toss ideas around and generally collaborate to make something cool.  Having a non-technical client kind of forced our team to do that.  Secondly, being interested in web development it was fun to take our requirements and really build out an improvement that could scale to a bigger user base.  None of the projects I had worked on in class or for fun had ever had a very big user base, so it always felt kind of amateurish.  Intentionally designing a system that could support so many users felt very professional, and gave me a confidence boost that I could work on large and scalable projects.  Lastly, working with a nonprofit with such a just purpose brought some satisfaction as well.  Having taken the assessment several times, I feel that it really is different from any other “bias test” out there, and I believe that the work being done at The Sum has a lot of value.  Implicit biases are everywhere in our world, and they’re extremely dangerous.  Working on the project felt like working to eliminate them, which was something I really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 22:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/19/powerofdifference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/19/powerofdifference.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graduation</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/graduation/grad2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/graduation/grad2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-9&quot;&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A little over a month ago I gratuated from the University of Virginia.  Because of the COVID-19 epidemic, this event didn’t go exactly as planned.  While I was still able to be in Charlottesville to celebrate, my family wasn’t able to join me, and the celebrations were slightly less formal.  That being said, it was really great to have an opportunity to reflect on everything that I’ve done and how much I’ve changed over the past four years.  UVA has meant a lot to me, and having that chance to reflect really put into perspective that the next phase of my life was ready to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The next phase has been coming slowly though.  The job that I had waiting for me at the end of the summer has been pushed back a bit, possibly as far as this winter.  It’s certainly not how I had hoped my “adult” life would start, but I’ve been trying to make the most of it.  It’s given me a chance to reflect on the mistakes I made in school, as well as the lessons I learned from them.  I don’t mean this in a pessimistic way though.  I’m really grateful for all the opportunities I had to live outside of my comfort zone.  Sometimes I lived too far outside of it, and I stumbled, but even those experiences taught me something, and at the end of the day I’m grateful for them.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;All of that being said, I think I’m ready for the next big thing.  It’s really easy to fall into nostalgia for what life was like at school, and I will cherish these years fondly.  But I’m ready for a new adventure, and I’m glad that I can move forward with that clarity.  In a way, this break has been very therapeutic, and given me a chance to center myself before embarking on the next journey.  I’m definitely getting antsy though, and really want to get started with adult life.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 20:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/18/graduation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/18/graduation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delta Sig Rush Site</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-bottom: 2%; width: 50%; margin-right: 2%; border-style: solid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;       
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/index.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/index.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/rushee_signin.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/rushee_signin.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/current_rushees.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/current_rushees.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/rushee.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/rushee.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/voting.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/voting.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/results.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/deltasigrush/results.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;         
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-prev&quot; href=&quot;#carousel&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
          &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-chevron-left&quot; style=&quot;font-size:36px; color: black&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Previous&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-next&quot; href=&quot;#carousel&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
          &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-chevron-right&quot; style=&quot;font-size:36px; color: black&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into my fourth year, one of the biggest yearly difficulties I faced was rush voting.  This is a process that can take legitimately up to 6 hours in each of the four rounds of voting, most of which occur on weeknights where the brothers have class the next day.  Rush is an essential process for a fraternity, as our existence and financial security rest solely on our ability to recruit new members.  While we had a system in place to track people coming through the door, it was clear to me that our system could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, there was no electronic system in place for voting.  This was by and large the biggest time sink in the entire process.  Voting is usually conducted by raise of hand or by placing votes in a bag.  This process was not efficient, and was one that I felt I could help optimize.  Challenges involved were making sure that every brother was able to access the site, that their votes and interactions with the rushees would be counted distinctly and attributed to their user accounts, and combining various technologies to make sure that we were tracking essential information on each of the rushees, including a picture of themselves that they take at the door and their contact information.  To do this, I used the Django framework, because I was familiar with it through my coursework, and because it handles a lot of the user account stuff natively.  This meant that I would be able to get a lot done without spending too much time on the little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insofar as meeting the stated goals of the project, the application was a big success.  Our tedious voting process was sped up a lot, and rush was conducted more efficiently all around.  There were also lessons learned though, and certainly room for improvement.  On one of the first nights of voting, we had a big problem with how long the site was taking to load, because we hadn’t tested it with so much data in the database before.  As it turns out, I had mistakenly saved a pretty sizable chunk of useless data that was originally stored when rushees took their pictures on the first night.  When many rushees were being loaded at once, this created a huge bottleneck on our process.  Fortunately, after a few hours of looking over the code I diagnosed the problem and fixed it before our next round of voting, but I learned an important lesson along the way about scaling when handling redundant data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the project worked so well for rush, I was asked if we could expand it to handle other fraternity functions, like our social events.  This expansion of functions is a project that I’m still working on, and have adapted into my GreekLink project that I talk about in another post.  But it’s been a lot of fun building this system for a group of my friends, which have been like a microcosm of a userbase.  The project taught me a lot about soliciting requirements and working with a nontechncial “client” of sorts, and I hope that the site I built can continue to be useful for our chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 01:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/04/deltasigrush.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/04/deltasigrush.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GreekLink</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-bottom: 2%; width: 50%; margin-right: 2%; border-style: solid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;       
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/greeklink_screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/greeklink_screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/list_active_screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/list_active_screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/resources_screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/resources_screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-item&quot;&gt;
                &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/settings_screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;d-block w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/greeklink/settings_screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;         
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-prev&quot; href=&quot;#carousel&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;prev&quot;&gt;
          &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-chevron-left&quot; style=&quot;font-size:36px; color: black&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Previous&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-control-next&quot; href=&quot;#carousel&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; data-slide=&quot;next&quot;&gt;
          &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-chevron-right&quot; style=&quot;font-size:36px; color: black&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreekLink is a software project a few friends and I have been working on.  At my fraternity chapter, we traditionally spend a lot of time conducting rush voting.  It’s a huge hassle, having to vote on every person that walks through the doors, with each of the four rounds of voting taking usually between 3 and 6 hours.  We used a web application designed by an alumni that wasn’t particularly user-friendly, and was in need of some improved tools to increase productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix these issues, I volunteered to redesign the site, with the primary goal being that we could conduct voting electronically.  In the past, voting was conducted by either a show of hands or the placing of chips in a bag.  These processes both took a matter of minutes to conduct, and my goal was to reduce this operation to a matter of seconds.  To do this, I designed a highly interactive web application using the Django python framework.  The site was deployed using Heroku, and managed everything involved in rush, from the scheduling of events to rushees signing in at the door to track attendance to the voting itself.  When it came time to conduct voting, rushees were pulled from our database of people who had attended the events, and users could place their votes on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there were a few hiccups to work through as we pushed the boundaries of how much load the application could handle from time to time, it eventually got to a point where things were running really smoothly.  So smoothly, in fact, that we decided to expand the site to include features for planning and managing social events throughout the semester.  This got my friends and I thinking, and we reached the conclusion that we could create a one-stop-shop for all of the people-management, planning, and communication that goes into running a Greek organization and sell the product for profit.  Thus, GreekLink was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is still a work in progress, many of the systems that were thrown together haphazardly for the initial product that my fraternity used have been deeply refined and polished.  We’ve been looking into elastic hosting options that will allow us to scale out to meet the needs of mulitple Greek organizations, and will hopefully even be able to facilitate communication amongst the community through our application.  This project has been a lot of fun, and I’m excited to see where it will go next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 01:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/04/greeklink.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/project/2020/06/04/greeklink.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the technical difficulties involved in maintaining the old version of connoryager.com, I’ve decided to mostly rebuild it and utilize the tools offered by Jekyll and Github to learn something new and make it a little simpler.  While my old blog was a lot of fun the maintenance of it was getting a little too much to handle.  The old site was run using an Apache server running on an old laptop in my parents house on a wireless connection to the router, where I had forwarded all HTTP and HTTPS requests to the laptop.  This was a lot of fun to setup, but not so much fun to fix everytime my mom unplugged the laptop to run the vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old site was a lot of fun though.  Basically every time I learned a new technology or technique, either in classes or that I taught myself, I would try to implement it on the site.  For example, I was pretty excited when I learned a bunch about running a database in my internship after my first year, so I set the site up with a database that would store comments and allow users to sign in.  Then my third year I took an intro to cybersecurity class that had a unit on SQL injections, and I realized that just using simple text input fields without sanitizing inputs was really not a very good idea.  So I fixed that up.  Then I realized I was overpaying massively for the services my hosting company was providing, so I decided to set up my own home server.  This learning by trial and error and using the site as a way to practice what I learned as I learned it was a lot of fun, and has contributed massively to my interest in web development.  But alas, it became a little too complex for its own good, and the maintenance on my end and the usability on the user’s end was becoming too weighed down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO, I am starting from scatch using the cheapest and most efficient technology I could find.  GitHub is a service I’m already familiar with, and just pushing to deploy a static site is a pretty intriguing concept.  It’s gonna take a little time for me to make this one as catchy and colorful as the last one, but hopefully as I go this will become more useful as a portfolio.  If you’re coming from the old connoryager.com, welcome to connoryager.com-2.0!  Thanks for checking in!  Otherwise, thanks for taking the time to visit the site and I hope you find it a pleasant stay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 15:47:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/01/new-site.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/01/new-site.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
